jobseeker.com.au 2019-04-15

# Jora

## Jora's commitment to maintaining your privacy

This Privacy Statement has been prepared by Job Seeker Pty Ltd (“ **Jora** ”). Jora owns and operates the website located at [jora.com](https://au.jora.com/) (across desktop, mobile, tablet and apps and including any subdomains) (“ **the Site** ”). This Privacy Statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Site. 

## Definitions

Where used in this Privacy Statement, the terms “personal information”, and “Australian Privacy Principle(s)” have the meaning attributed to those terms in the Privacy Act (Cth) 1988 (“ **Privacy Act** ”). 

In this Privacy Statement: 

  * any reference to **“Jora”, “we”, “us”** and **“our”** refers to Job Seeker Pty Ltd and each of its related bodies corporate (as that term is defined in the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth)); 
  * “ **Advertiser** ” refers to individuals or entities that post job ads on our Site or otherwise use the Site to source potential Candidates for job vacancies; 
  * “ **Candidates** ” refers to users of the Site and “ **Registered Users** ” refers to Candidates who register on the Site; and
  * Candidates, Advertisers and users who otherwise subscribe for Jora products, services or information offered via the Site are referred to generically in this Statement as “ **visitors** ”, " **users** " or " **you** ", unless the context provides that only Candidates, Registered Users or Advertisers are being referred to. 

## Collecting information on Jora visitors

Jora collects non-personal information on Site visits by users including, without limitation, which sections of the Site are most frequently visited, how often, and for how long. This data is always used as aggregated, non-personal information, and may be shared with Jora related parties or service providers to provide them with information relating to how Jora visitors 'use' the Site. This is done for the purpose of providing you with the best and most efficient career management and recruitment services. 

## IP Addresses

Jora's web servers gather your IP address to assist with the diagnosis of problems or support issues with our services, and to monitor the use of our Site. 

## Cookies 

Jora uses cookies and applets to provide Candidates with a better browsing experience and tailor advertisements that appear, (on the Site or other websites) to your browsing preferences. These cookies and applets collect non-personal information such as preferences and click activity for measurement and for features such as remembering your search criteria for the 'My Search' function. 

Jora uses cookies and scripts in respect of Advertisers to assist Jora in improving website performance, making business decisions, aiding in error reporting and testing new functionality. These cookies and scripts collect non-personal information such as preferences and click activity for measurement and for Site features. 

If you do not wish to have cookies active whilst you browse the Site you can "opt out" by modifying the privacy options in your browser. However, doing so will prevent access to some areas of the Site and limit your use of some of the Jora services. 

In addition to the above, where users access the Jora mobile applications (" **Jora Apps** ") we use third party software development kits (SDK's) and services which collect non personal information relating to your use of the Jora Apps, including tracking of app installs and re-engagement. This information is used to tailor and measure advertisements to install and/or use the Jora Apps which appear on third party sites/apps and are targeted towards users' usage preferences. 

If you want to opt-out from the collection and usage of information for advertisement targeting you can do so by enabling "Limit Ad Tracking" (Settings>Privacy>Advertising) on your iOS device or by enabling the "Opting out of interest-based ads" option (Settings>Services>Ads) on your Android device. By opting out from ad targeting Jora and its third party providers will not use the collected information to target ads to you, however the information collected may continue to be used by Jora for, amongst other things, estimation of user numbers, advertising fraud detection and debugging. 

## Third Party Measurement

In order to better understand our users, Jora utilises third party measurement companies to assess Site and mobile Site traffic. A tracking code is used to collect the following information on the usage of the Site: 

  * The number of page views (or page impressions) that occur on the Site;
  * The number of unique visitors to the Site;
  * How long these unique visitors (on average) spend on the Site when they do visit; and
  * Common entry and exit points into the Site.

This aggregated, non-personal information is collated and provided to Jora to assist in analysing the usage of the Site. This data is also accessible by media organisations and research companies, for the purpose of conducting industry comparisons with other Internet websites. 

## Collecting information on Registered Users

As part of registering with Jora, we collect personal information about Registered Users in order for Registered Users to take full advantage of Jora's services. To do this it will be necessary for Registered Users to provide additional information to Jora. 

## Registration

Becoming a Registered User allows you to take advantage of more of the tools, services and resources that may assist you in finding a job. To become a Registered User you will need to submit some personal information such as your name and email address. You may access your information at any time by clicking 'Edit Profile' on the ['My Jobs > My Account'](https://au.jora.com/account) section of the Site. You may also delete your account entirely by using the [Contact Us](https://au.jora.com/contact/new?subject=Personal%20data%20request) form on our Site. 

Jora may also use this information in order to customise the service we provide to you. For example, Jora may use this information to create a Jora Profile that you may choose to use in the future. However, we will never activate this Jora Profile (or any other service) without your express consent. 

## Email Alerts

Email Alerts is an optional service available to Registered Users. To use Email Alerts Registered Users must provide their email address, and information relating to their employment preferences so that Jora can notify Registered Users via email of jobs within their specified criteria. Registered Users can modify or delete their Email Alerts preferences at any time by going to the ' _[My Alerts](https://au.jora.com/account/email_alerts)_ ' area of the Site. 

## Online Applications

Making an online application to a job advertisement on Jora is a free and optional service that requires Candidates to complete mandatory fields (for example first name, last name and email) so that the Advertiser can identify and contact the applicant. 

Applications, including attachments such as resumes and cover letters, are either submitted through: 

  * the Site; or
  * another website on which the Advertiser’s job ad appears which you access via a link on our Site. 

If you make an application via the Site we will retain that application on our systems. 

Any questions you have relating to a position advertised on Jora, your online application and/or the status of your application should be directed directly to the Advertiser or their nominated agent, not Jora. 

Advertisers must comply with all relevant obligations under privacy laws relating to the use and disclosure of personal information. The use of your information (personal or otherwise) by Advertisers is not within the control of Jora and we do not accept responsibility for the conduct of these companies. 

## Advertisers

Jora collects the company name, email address and mobile phone number of Advertisers from publicly available third party content. Jora uses these details to enable Candidates to apply to jobs. 

Where an Advertiser posts a job directly on Jora, Jora will collect and store the details of the job ad. Jora may distribute those advertisements on other channels at its discretion. 

## Communications from Jora

Jora may also provide you with selected information about job placement and career-related topics in email communications. From time to time Jora may also contact you by telephone. Jora may also make Registered Users and Advertisers aware of additional products and services which form part of your relationship with Jora. Users may opt out of receiving any such communications by clicking 'unsubscribe' in the footer of an email received. 

## Contractors

Jora may also disclose your personal information to Jora's service providers and contractors from time to time but only for the purpose of assisting us to deliver the products and services we offer to you. 

## Related Bodies Corporate

Jora may also disclose your personal information to Jora's related bodies corporate from time to time but only for the purpose of assisting Jora and its related bodies corporate to deliver the products and services offered to you. 

## Storage & Security of Personal Information

Jora takes all reasonable steps to ensure the security of our system and to protect your information from misuse, interference and loss as well as unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Jora allows you to access your information at any time to keep it accurate and up to date. Any information which we hold for you is stored on secure servers, either in Australia or overseas (including the United States of America), that are protected in controlled facilities. 

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality and privacy of any personal information held by Jora. Except in the case of breaches of our obligations under privacy laws to protect your personal information, Jora will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of your personal information. 

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the Site. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user, or any other breach of security relating to your account. 

## Access to Your Information

Unless you become a Registered User, subscribe to email alerts or become an Advertiser, Jora does not collect information that identifies you personally. In addition to the methods listed above for users to update their information, any user is able to at any time request that Jora deletes any personal information held by completing and submitting the form on our [Contact Us](https://au.jora.com/contact/new?subject=Personal%20data%20request) page. Candidates who have applied for any position on the Site are also able to request their personal information directly from those Advertisers. 

## Data Transfers

Jora's corporate headquarters are located in Australia, and so your information may be transferred to, and/or stored in, Australia. Sometimes, we transfer or disclose information to third party contractors including to persons and businesses outside Australia including in the Philippines. These transfers are made in order to assist us to provide you with the products and services we offer you. Where we transfer information to persons outside Australia we take reasonable steps to ensure that the recipients of such information do not breach privacy laws in relation to that information. 

## Feedback and Complaints about privacy and the Jora website

Jora welcomes ideas and feedback about all aspects of the Site. Jora stores feedback that users send to us. This feedback may be used to administer and refine the service we provide and may be shared with Jora’s related body corporates or service providers either in aggregate form or with specific identifying characteristics removed. 

If you have any complaints about our dealings with your personal information including any breaches by us of any privacy laws or any questions regarding this Privacy Statement you are able to submit that complaint or query by contacting us at [support@jora.com](mailto:support@jora.com) or post using online form method as detailed in the “Contact Us” paragraph below. 

Any complaints received by us will be referred to our compliance team for prompt investigation and a written response will be provided to you as soon as possible. 

Should you not be satisfied with the resolution of any complaints made you are able to seek further redress through the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (see <http://www.oaic.gov.au/> for further information). 

## Privacy & Site Changes

From time to time, Jora may review and update its Privacy Statement. Revised versions will be made available on the Site. 

## Contact Us

If you have any feedback or questions about this Privacy Statement, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with Jora, you can contact us in the following ways: 

Email: [support@jora.com](mailto:support@jora.com)

Web: visit our ‘Contact Us’ page and fill out the online form 

## Obtaining a Copy of this Privacy Statement

If you require a hard copy of this Privacy Statement or a copy in some other format to suit your particular needs please contact us using any of the methods detailed in the “Contact Us” paragraph above, and we will arrange for a suitable copy to be provided to you. 

## European Union

If you are a resident of the European Union for the purposes of the GDPR, then in addition to what is set out above, the following applies to you. 

For the purposes of this section, the following definitions apply: 

“ **GDPR** ” means the General Data Protection Regulation, being Regulation 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council; and 

“ **Personal Data** ” has the meaning attributed to that term in the GDPR. 

Jora is a data controller and processor for the purposes of the GDPR and by your consenting to this Privacy Statement Jora is able to processes your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Our Contact details are set out in the “Contact Us” paragraph above. 

In providing its services to you, Jora may make use of a number of automated processes using your Personal Data and your activity on our Site as tracked by us, in order to provide more tailored and relevant services to you such as providing recommended job opportunities to you through email communication and on the Site. 

Jora may also use such data in automated processes aimed at providing more tailored and relevant services to Advertisers. 

In addition to your rights set out above, you may: 

  * update or rectify any of the Personal Data that we hold about you, in the manner described in the “Access to Your Information” paragraph above.
  * withdraw your consent to Jora’s use of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Statement by deleting your account. This will also delete all the Personal Data about you which we hold. This can be done by completing and submitting the form on our [Contact Us](https://au.jora.com/contact/new?subject=Personal%20data%20request) page.
  * request that Jora 
    * provides you with a copy of the Personal Data Jora holds about you in a portable and machine readable form; or 
    * share your Personal Data with a nominated third party;

by completing and submitting the form on our [Contact Us](https://au.jora.com/contact/new?subject=Personal%20data%20request) page. 

Should you have any concerns in relation to Jora’s collection and/or processing of your Personal Data, then in addition to the process set out in the “Feedback and Complaints about privacy and the Jora website” set out above (including the right to complain to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner), you have the right to complain to a supervisory authority (within the meaning of the GDPR). 

Our representative for the purposes of the GDPR is set out below: 

MCF Legal Technology Solutions Limited 

Riverside One 

Sir John Rogerson’s Quay 

Dublin 2 

IRELAND 

Email: jora@mcf.ie
